accessmylibrary.com 2019-06-04

# Privacy – Cengage

Cengage is committed to protecting children’s privacy. This means:

  1. We do not allow any children under 16 to register with Cengage, and we do not knowingly collect or use any personal information pertaining to children under 16 for our own purposes. If you believe that an underage child has provided personal information to us, please contact [privacy@cengage.com](mailto:privacy@cengage.com) so that we may delete the information and take other appropriate steps.
  2. We provide products and solutions to educational institutions that require us to process K-12 student information. We only collect and process information pertaining to these children as a processor for the educational institutions. We do not use any of this student information for our own purposes. We comply with all applicable laws related to student data processing, including the Family and Educational Rights Privacy Act (FERPA), the Children’s Online Protection Act, and U.S. state student privacy laws.  

Cengage is providing this supplemental privacy notice to give individuals in the European Economic Area (EEA) the additional information required by the EU General Data Protection Regulation. These provisions, together with the statements in the [Cengage Privacy Notice,](https://www.cengage.com/privacy/statement) explain our practices with regard to EEA personal data.

This information is being provided by Cengage, Inc. for itself and its subsidiaries:

Cengage, Inc.  
Privacy Office  
20 Channel Center  
Boston MA 02210

Cengage, Inc. is based in the United States. Our representative in the EEA is:

Cengage Learning (EMEA) Limited

Cheriton House  
North Way  
Walworth Business Park  
Andover  
Hampshire  
SP10 5BE

Registration Number: Z2487772

The [Cengage Privacy Notice](https://www.cengage.com/privacy/statement) explains the reasons why we process your Personal Information. We only process Personal Information when we have a legal basis for the processing, such as:

  * To fulfill a contract with you or your school
  * For closely-related purposes, such as payment processing and financial account management, contract management, website administration, business continuity and disaster recovery, security and fraud prevention, corporate governance, reporting and legal compliance
  * With your consent (or provided you have not objected, as may be appropriate under applicable law), such to provide you with marketing communications  

We may also process your Personal Information for the purposes of our legitimate interests (or for the legitimate interests of your school, provided that such processing shall not outweigh your rights and freedoms.) In particular, we may process your Personal Information as needed to:

  * Protect you, us or others from threats (such as security threats or fraud) or cheating, 
  * Comply with the laws that are applicable to us around the world,
  * Enable or administer our business, such as for quality control, consolidated reporting, and customer service, 
  * Manage corporate transactions, such as mergers or acquisitions, and  
  * Understand and improve our business or customer relationships generally. 

We may use profiling and analytics to understand how individuals interact with our educational materials, such as assess engagement and improve learning outcomes, and product development purposes. For example, we may use analytics to study the amount of time that individuals spend on specific content items and we may infer engagement from this process. These analytics also help us understand and improve our materials, as we can determine what materials are more or less accessible to students. We may also use analytics for course integrity purposes, such as to identify individuals that may be cheating.

We will not make automated decisions about you that may significantly affect you, unless (1) the decision is necessary as part of a contract that we have with you, (2) we have your explicit consent, or (3) we are required by law to use the technology.

In most cases, you are not required by law to provide any Personal Information to Cengage. You are required to provide certain Personal Information to enable us to enter into a contract with you so that you can use our products and services. Our registration forms indicate which data elements are required for our contracts. If you do not provide these data elements, we cannot do business with you.

As noted in the [Cengage Privacy Notice](https://www.cengage.com/privacy/statement), you always have the right to object to our marketing communications. To opt-out of emails, simply click the link labeled “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any email we send you. To revoke permissions that you may have given to send text messages, text STOP in response to any message.    
Cengage also respects the rights of EEA residents to access, correct and request erasure or restriction of their personal information as required by law. This means: 

  * You generally have a right to know whether or not Cengage maintains your Personal Information. If we do have your personal information, we will provide you with a copy (subject to the rights of others). If your information is incorrect or incomplete, you have the right to ask us to update it.  
  * You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Information.
  * You may also ask us to delete or restrict your personal information. 

To exercise these rights, please contact us via email to [privacy@cengage.com](mailto:privacy@cengage.com) or write us at the address above, and a member of our Privacy Team will assist you.  Please understand that we may need to verify your identify before we can process your request.   

If you believe that we have processed your Personal Information in violation of applicable law, you may file a complaint with the Cengage Privacy Office or with a supervisory authority.

As noted in the [Cengage Privacy Notice](https://www.cengage.com/privacy/statement), your Personal Information may be transferred to, stored at or processed in the United States and other countries which may not have equivalent privacy or data protection laws. 

We generally use approved Standard Contractual Clauses to assure that Personal Information is adequately protected when it is transferred out of the European Economic Area or Switzerland, but we may also make transfers to recipients with approved Binding Corporate Rules or to recipients in the United States who have certified to the EU-US and/or Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework. 

Please contact us via email to [privacy@cengage.com](mailto:privacy@cengage.com) if you would like more information about cross-border transfers or to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses.    

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as the information is needed for the purposes set forth in Section 3 above and for any additional period that may be required or permitted by law. You may request that we delete your Personal Information by contacting us via email to [privacy@cengage.com](mailto:privacy@cengage.com). Unless we are required by law to retain your information, we will delete it within 30 days of your request.  

Please contact us if you have any questions or comments about our privacy practices or this Privacy Notice. You can always reach us via email to [privacy@cengage.com](mailto:privacy@cengage.com). You can also reach us via mail to the addresses given above.

Certain Cengage businesses, like Ed2Go, administer websites that provide course materials and services for educational institutions and companies. Information collected on these websites is only used by us to support our clients and provide the services requested by the course instructors. We do not use this information for our own purposes. Most educational institution student course records are also protected by the Family and Educational Rights Privacy Act (FERPA). For information on your company or school's privacy policies, please contact the administration.

Our hosted websites may offer students and professionals the opportunity to interact directly with Cengage Learning.  If so, the [Cengage  Privacy Notice](http://www.cengage.com/privacy/statement) **** will apply to that information.

Cengage Learning, Inc. and its affiliates collect U.S. Social Security numbers and other sensitive Personal Information in the ordinary course of its business. We have implemented reasonable technical, physical and administrative safeguards to help protect sensitive Personal Information from unlawful use and unauthorized disclosure. All Cengage workers are required to follow these established safeguards, which include the following:

  * Access to sensitive Personal Information is limited to those workers and service providers who have a need to access the information to perform tasks for Cengage. Sensitive Personal Information is only disclosed to third parties in accordance with Cengage's established privacy and security policy.
  * Cengage will only disclose sensitive Personal Information (1) to those service providers, auditors, advisors and/or successors in interest who are legally or contractually obligated to protect them, or (2) as required or permitted by law.

If you have any questions, please contact us at [privacy@cengage.com.](mailto:privacy@cengage.com)

California Civil Code Section 1798 allows California residents to ask companies with whom they have an established business relationship to provide certain information about the companies’ sharing of Personal Information with third parties for direct marketing purposes.

California customers who wish to request further information about our compliance with this law or have questions or concerns about our privacy practices may contact us at [privacy@cengage.com](mailto:privacy@cengage.com) or by writing to:

Cengage Learning, Inc.  
Privacy Office  
20 Channel Center  
Boston MA 02210
